Well, it's time for step two, which is to properly organize our project by importing all of our sprites.
Now remember, for this stage, we are not going to import our start screen and other features into
the game.
As.
Remember with our workflow we discussed before, we will do this later on.
This also makes things a little less overwhelming.
So that's it.
However, if you don't want to follow along and manually import these things, you can also download
the starter version of the project.
And just like before by clicking this button, then clicking load from your computer, then selecting
the starter Project.
Here you will see that we have all our sprites ready to go.
And yes, this also includes our start screen sprites and our buttons.
That's it.
However, as I want you to learn the process of developing a game properly so you can do it by yourself
and practice makes perfect.
Let's do this the proper way.
Now let's bring in our first sprite.
So clicking this button here we can select our player sprite which is located under this folder.
As you can see, there are three different sprites to choose from, and this is because there are these
different costumes.
So we can just select any one of these as we will add the rest just now.
So hitting open here you will see our player sprite.
Now before we add the obstacles let's quickly add the other costumes for this sprite.
So moving over to the costumes tab and clicking here.
We can then select the other two costumes like so.
With that done, we can now import our tree sprite, which are the obstacles in our game.
So clicking this button here and then moving over to our tree sprite folder here.
Just like before, we can select any one of these obstacle sprites.
And once we have done so, we can move over to our costumes tab and then select the rest of them.
And there you go.
We have all our sprites ready to go.
And before we move on to our final sprite, there are just a few modifications we need to make, which
is how this Bush costume is just way too large, so we can simply select it and shrink it down like
this.
Also, we can do the same for these stones as they're also a bit big.
Okay, nice.
So before we add in our snow sprite, let's just size these trees so they look right.
Because as you can see, they are definitely still too big.
So for our tree sprite let's set its size to 50, which looks a lot smaller compared to our player,
which doesn't really make sense unless our player is some sort of giant.
So let's set our player sprite a lot smaller, let's say 17.
So now as you can see, that looks a lot better.
So the last thing is our snow pixels.
And this time we are going to make our own.
Not to do this.
Instead of selecting choose a sprite, we're going to click this button here, which allows us to design
sprites of our own.
So with this we can select the square shape.
And before you do anything, we need to change the color to be more gray like snow.
So selecting this button here we can decrease the saturation and the brightness.
And as you can see we have a nice gray color.
So with that we can draw a small square right in the middle of our screen.
And basically because we want this to be like a snow trout we can decrease the size.
And here just playing with it until you find something that looks right.
And that looks okay.
So with that, we need more snow pixels for the other ski.
But instead of doing all that again, we can just hit this duplicate button.
And while we're at it, let's give our sprites a name like Snow Pixel one and a Snow Pixel two.
And there you have it.
All our sprites are imported and ready to come to life, so get ready because these next few lessons
are going to be lots of fun.